Look,
你看呀
what exactly
你说咱们女儿
is our daughter up to?
在干嘛到底
She's just on her phone.
不就看手机吗
Keep it down!
轻点
I'm not talking
我说的重点
about that.
不是在看手机
Don't you remember?
你忘了吗
The way we're like
当时我们恋爱时候的
when we're dating,
感觉了
constantly clutching our pagers,
整天抱着传呼机手不放
terrified of missing a single message.
生怕错过一条信息
And when we got a message,
当一条信息来了以后
we'd just stare at it
就拿着看着
and giggle like fools.
呵呵呵地傻笑
We need to figure out a way
我们得想办法
to check her phone.
看看她的手机
Ouch!
哎呦
My belly hurts so badly.
肚子好疼
What's the matter?
怎么回事
I can't take it anymore.
我不行了
Let me see which
这臭小子
punk it is.
我倒看看是谁
Hey, I zoomed it in.
唉 大图 大图
It is English for college entrance exams.
怎么是高考必读英语啊
Our daughter was actually studying.
咱 咱女儿居然在学习
See, it was just your imagination.
所以说 你想多了
That day on the bus,
那天我在公交车上
I saw her
明明看着
being very intimate
她跟一个男同学
with a boy.
举止很亲密啊
Seeing is not always believing.
眼见不一定为实
Maybe you saw it wrong.
可能你看错了呢
What's with the drawing and the photo?
那你说画跟照片
Photo?
照片
They are friends.
关系很好
It's normal to have a photo.
有张照片很正常的呀
As for the drawing...
就是画吧
When I was young,
我年轻的时候
I drew countless beautiful girls.
画过无数漂亮的姑娘
It doesn't necessarily mean
也不见得
I had any relationship with them.
一定跟我有什么关系
Xiao Datu, what's that supposed to mean?
肖大图 你什么意思
Except for you,
除了你
the others were just figure models.
其他都是绘画工具
Our little girl,
咱们闺女
up early and staying up late,
起早贪黑的
she's been focused on ABCD.
就知道看ABCD呀
How could she possibly be in puppy love?
怎么可能早恋呢
Besides,
再说了
our daughter is way out of
那个什么凌冬
that Ling Dong and
还有兰灰灰
Lan Huihui's league.
咱闺女哪看得上
Right?
是不
That being said,
这么说
you do have a point.
你说得也有点道理
Was it really just my imagination?
难道我真的想多了
Comrade Guo Ying,
郭颖同志
you are just too sensitive.
你啊 就是太敏感
Cut it out!
行了 行了
Come on,
快
mop the floor.
抹地
It's done.
抹好了
Do it again!
再去擦
Again?
还擦
Why?
擦几遍哪
Come on, have some milk.
来来来 喝点牛奶
Comrade Xiao,
老肖同志
just confess.
老实交代
Have you betrayed me?
你有没有出卖组织
Ma'am,
报告组织
I have not.
老肖同志没有
Then what's with you and mom
那你最近跟我妈
acting all weird recently?
鬼鬼祟祟搞什么呢
Is she aware that
她是不是发现了
I've been learning drawing?
我学画画的事
Dad also has a question for you.
正好老爸也有问题问你
Let's trade.
咱们交换答案
Are you in love?
你是不是早恋了
In love?
早恋
So,
搞半天
your parents misunderstood
你爸妈误会
that we were your love interests.
我们是你早恋对象
Yeah, I didn't expect it either.
对啊 我也没有想到
It was a fluke
也算是误打误撞
that dispelled your mom's concerns.
打消了阿姨的顾虑
So, inviting us
合着叫我们俩
to have dinner at your house
去你们家吃饭
was to test us,
就是试探我们俩
to see who was your love interest,
谁才是你的早恋对象
right?
是吗
So, who did she think that was?
那 阿姨猜的是谁呢
Their exact words were,
他们的原话是
they could tell at a glance
他们一看就知道
that we are
我们是坚不可摧的
real brothers-in-arms.
革命友谊
They should have picked me.
再怎么应该猜我吧
After all, I'm so cute and charming,
毕竟我这么可爱又迷人
fun and handsome.
风趣又帅气
Don't flatter yourself.
想多了吧
You were excluded from the start.
一开始就把你排除了
Why?
为什么
Didn't you notice her mom's gaze?
没看见阿姨的眼神吗
It was fixed on me the whole time.
一直在我身上
Narcissism is a disease.
自恋是一种病
You need treatment.
得治
Sorry,
不好意思
confidence is a talent.
自信是种天赋
It's not something you treat.
没法治
I don't have time to watch you two bicker.
我没时间看你们斗嘴了
I have to leave.
我要走了
My exam is next week.
下周就要联考了
If I don't pass,
要是真没考过
my dream of studying fine arts is over.
我就真的学艺无望了
We can't let that happen.
那不行
We all made a pact
咱们都约好了
to attend Jing University together.
要一起上京大的
We can't let our hard work
不能让咱们做的
go in vain.
这些努力白费
What does this
你这个联考
exam cover?
都要考什么呀
It includes color, sketching and drawing.
就是色彩 速写和素描
Color is straightforward.
色彩好说
But sketching and drawing,
速写和素描
I'm not sure what kind of
也不知道会出
tasks will be given.
什么样的考题
Don't worry.
没关系
Like all other exams,
跟文化考试一样
just practice as much as you could.
上题海战术
Just practice to draw
练习身边
everything around you.
一切可以练习的事物
Apprentice,
徒弟
are we done yet?
好了吗
I can't hold it much longer.
快坚持不住了
I'm almost there.
快了 快了
Just ten more minutes.
就最后十分钟
Ten minutes?
十分钟
No way, make it three.
不行了 三分钟
Seven minutes?
七分钟行不行
No, five minutes.
五分钟
I can't hold it anymore.
我真的坚持不住了
Six minutes, just six minutes.
六分钟 就六分钟
Hurry up.
快点
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
hang in there.
坚持住
You do have a conscience, geek.
算你有良心啊 呆子
Done!
搞定
Hey, Lan Jinghui, Lan Jinghui!
兰靖灰 兰靖灰 兰靖灰
This is...
这 这是
A kettle.
烧水壶啊
Will the exam include something like this?
考试会考这样的题吗
It's all about predicting, right?
押题嘛 不就这样嘛
Just practice with everything you've got.
题海战术
You can't overlook
不能放过
any possibility.
任何一个可能性
Mom.
妈
Hey.
唉
Are you alright?
你没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
I'm just sorting vegetables.
这不是择菜
I'll cook soon.
一会儿做饭嘛
Keep up with your studies.
好好学习啊
Mr. Wang,
王老师
regarding the essays
我上次给您发
I sent you last time.
那个散文集
Did you get a chance to read it?
您看过了吗
This is...
你是那个
Xu Mengyu.
徐梦予
Oh yeah, I remember you.
对对对 我想起来了
I'm short on time,
我时间不多
so I'll be brief.
就长话短说了啊
Your essays are quite good.
你的散文不错
Your mother mentioned it several times.
你妈妈跟我提了很多次
You have a passion for literature, good.
喜欢文学呢 是件好事
But you still have a long way to go
但离出书啊
before you can publish a book.
还是有差距的
Feel free to submit again next time.
欢迎你下次投稿啊
That's all. Goodbye.
就这样 同学 再见
Mengyu?
梦予
You are...
你是
I'm Ma Mao.
我是马茂
Remember me?
你忘了
Back in middle school,
初中那会儿
I used to get tutoring in essay writing
我在你妈妈那儿
from your mom.
补习过作文
Oh, you're Ma Mao.
你是马茂师哥
It's been so long.
好久不见啊
I almost didn't recognize you.
我差点没认出来
Yes.
是啊
If I hadn't been following you on Weibo,
要不是我一直关注你
I might not have recognized you either.
可能我也认不出来了
You've gotten prettier.
变漂亮了
You've been following me on Weibo?
你关注我
Yeah,
对啊
I was checking you on Weibo just now.
我刚才还有刷你微博呢
I've read everything
你上面发的文字
that you have posted.
我都看了
I like them a lot.
特别喜欢
I've discovered that you can understand
我发现从文字
someone through their writing.
也可以了解一个人
I think you've got talent.
我觉得你很有才华
Thanks.
谢谢师哥
Actually, all that
其实那些
was just me scribbling away.
都是我胡乱写的
Have a seat. Let's chat.
你先坐吧 我们坐下聊
OK.
好
You know, I believe
我觉得呀
you'll definitely
你以后
become a famous writer in the future.
一定能成为一个作家
I'm signing up right now
我现在就报名
to be your number one fan.
做你头号粉丝
Have you read my articles?
你有看过我写的文章吗
Of course.
当然了
I was even thinking of leaving a comment.
本来我还想和你留言呢
I was worried you might not remember me.
但怕你不记得我
Oh, right,
对了
we should exchange contacts.
我们留个联系方式吧
Sure, that would be great.
好 当然可以
Whenever you have something new,
那你以后有新的作品
make sure to share it with me.
记得分享给我
We can discuss it together.
我们可以一起探讨
I could really use someone
我正好也需要一个
to give me feedback
可以在写作上
on my writing.
给我提意见的人
It's been such a long time, hasn't it?
真的好久不见了
Yeah.
是啊
You've changed so much.
你变化好多啊
Yeah,
我刚才都没认出来你
I only realized it was you
我走过来
when I walked over here.
才发现你在这边坐着
Is that so?
就 是吗
Look at you, can't wait to eat.
看你馋的
Don't eat too much meat, OK?
不许多吃肉啊
Why isn't Xiaohua back yet?
小画怎么还没回来
Call her and check.
打个电话问问她
Oh.
哦
She said
她说
she won't be home for dinner today.
她今天就不回家吃饭了
Isn't there no tutoring today?
不是今天没有补习班吗
Oh.
哦
Here's the thing.
是这样的
Their coursework at school is
他们学校现在功课
really intense lately,
特别地紧张
so she said
所以呢
she's staying at school to study.
她说她就在学校自习了
Is that so?
是吗
Darling, what are you doing?
老婆你 这是干嘛呢
You said Xiaohua is studying, right?
你不说小画在补习嘛
I was thinking,
我想啊
she's been studying so hard lately,
她最近特别用功
I'm worried about her nutrition.
怕营养不良
I'll bring some fish soup to her,
我弄点鱼汤给她送过去
so she can get a good boost.
让她好好补一补呢
Help me with this.
唉 帮我一块夹
Ah, right,
唉 对了啊
after I leave,
我走了以后
you're not allowed to eat too much meat.
你不许多吃肉啊
You have a fatty liver.
有脂肪肝
You got it?
听到了没有
I'm taking this away. No more for you.
这收掉 不许私藏
Sweetie, pick up the phone.
女儿接电话呀
Please, pick up!
赶快接电话呀
Oh, gosh!
我的天哪
Yo, yo, yo,
喂喂喂
where are all of you?
你们都在哪儿呀
Where are you?
都在哪儿
What are you doing?
干嘛呢
Come out to eat.
出来吃饭
Eat, eat, eat!
吃饭 吃饭 吃饭
I think I saw
我好像看到了
someone very familiar.
一特熟悉的人
Hello, auntie.
阿姨好
Qingtian.
晴天
Are you done with school?
放学了
Yes.
对
But I have to study in here for a while.
不过一会儿还有自习课
Where's Xiaohua?
咱们家小画呢
Is she in the study room?
在自习室
Right.
对
Auntie, why are you here?
阿姨 你怎么来了
Well, I'm bringing Xiaohua
我啊 给我们家小画
some fish soup.
送点营养汤
She's been studying so hard.
这孩子太刻苦了
Auntie,
阿姨
how about
要不然
I go up with you?
我跟你一起上去吧
It's OK.
不用了
I'll find her myself.
我自己找她去
You
你呀
just go and focus on your study.
就乖乖地去学习
Later.
拜拜
Why isn't she picking up?
怎么不接电话呀
Xiaohua's mom is here.
小画妈妈来了
DEFCON 1, DEFCON 1!
拉响一级警报
What do we do now?
现在怎么办
Others, go and stall her mom.
其他人去拦住阿姨
I'll go find her with Lan Jinghui.
我跟兰靖灰去找肖小画
Roger that.
收到
You first.
要不你先走
No, no, auntie,
别别别 阿姨
you go first.
您先过 您先过
Auntie, are you looking for someone or...
阿姨 您是找人还是
No,
不是
I was actually headed to
我想到你们学校的
the study room.
自习室
It's such a large campus.
你们学校太大了
I've been having trouble finding it.
我找不到
Oh, the study room.
自习室啊
Where is it?
在哪儿呢
I can guide you there, if you'd like?
我带您去 好不好
Thank you so much.
谢谢 谢谢
No problem.
没事 没事 没事
Please,
阿姨 您先走
after you.
您先走 您先走
Thanks.
同学 谢谢你
I've got it.
没事的 可以
Your school is huge, huh?
你们学校真大啊
It's alright.
还行吧
Where is she?
人呢
I'm not sure.
不知道啊
These buildings all have
这楼都是板楼
a similar look, don't they?
长得感觉差不多
Yes,
对
because they're all in the same style.
因为建筑风都是一样的
Is that so?
这样的是吧
So, it's this way?
往这儿走吗
Actually, it's that way.
不不 往那边走
Oh, OK.
往那边走
Yes, that's right.
对对对
It's a big place.
学校真大
I'd be lost without your help.
不是你我还真找不到呢
I'm happy to assist.
没事 我这人善良
Hold on,
不对呀 同学
haven't we circled back?
是不是我们又绕回来了
I don't think so.
没有啊
But
不对 不对
I remember passing
刚才我们走过去的时候
these same spots earlier,
我看到就是这些
and now we're back again.
现在又回来了
You might be mistaken, auntie.
阿姨 您肯定看错了
We didn't pass these before.
刚才没有这些东西
Wait,
不会
It seems you
同学
aren't familiar with the layout either.
看来你也不熟悉路啊
No, I'm...
没有
It's fine.
没事 没事
You go on, I'll find my way.
你玩你的 我自己找
Please, auntie,
别 阿姨
let me take you there.
我带您过去吧
It's fine.
没事
Come on,
阿姨
auntie.
阿姨 阿姨
That's fine.
不用 不用
Thanks.
谢谢你
It's very nice of you.
你真是个好同学
I appreciate it.
很好啊
Go on with your day.
你自己玩
No, auntie!
不是 阿姨
She's heading to the fine arts building,
阿姨往艺术楼走了
the fine arts building.
往艺术楼走了
Where is she?
在哪呢
When will she be here?
什么时候来
Ah, she's heading this way.
唉 来了
She's coming.
来了 来了 来了
Quickly, quickly.
快快快
These stairs are filthy;
这台阶怎么那么脏啊
they need a good mop.
得使劲拖
Auntie!
阿姨
I'm so sorry.
对不起 对不起
Let me clean your sneakers!
我帮您擦干净
Come on.
来来来
No,
别别别
It's fine, it's fine.
没事 没事
Stop...
别
The cloth is dirty.
抹布脏
I'll just use my hands. I'm used to it.
我用手 我专业的
Auntie, don't worry...
阿姨 你放心
Chen Luyang,
陈璐阳
give me some water to rinse my paintbrush.
借我点水洗个画笔
Hey...
那个
Just keep quiet!
你给我闭嘴
Mom,
妈
I apologize, I was wrong.
对不起 我错了
What did you do wrong?
错哪儿了
I shouldn't have lied to you.
我不应该骗您
I shouldn't have deceived you.
不应该撒谎
And what else?
还有呢
That's all.
没有了
Why did you keep it a secret from me
那你为什么瞒着我
that you were learning to paint?
去学画画
About that,
这件事情
I don't think I did anything wrong.
我觉得我没有做错
Xiaohua,
小画
I'm not against you painting,
妈妈不是反对你画画
but at this crucial moment
但是现在
before the college entrance exams,
在高考这个节骨眼上
you need to concentrate
你要集中精力
and dedicate yourself to your studies.
好好地学习
Learning something
什么学艺术啊
like arts
这些东西
will only distract you.
都会分散你的精力的
You're a student,
你现在是学生
so you need to focus on your studies.
就要好好读书
Prepare for the college entrance exams.
好好地去参加高考
Do you understand?
懂吗
I've been practicing painting because of
我就是为了高考
the college entrance exam.
学的画画
I'm aiming for the Fine Arts College at Jing University.
我还想考京大美院呢
Jing University's Fine Arts College?
考京大美院
It's a spur-of-the-moment decision.
你简直是心血来潮吧
You find painting fun for now,
你现在知道画画很好玩
but what happens when
三分钟热度过去了以后
your brief enthusiasm wears off?
怎么办
It's not brief enthusiasm,
我不是心血来潮
and it won't wear off.
不是三分钟热度
I've thought about it very carefully.
我想得很清楚了
I'm truly committed to it.
我是认真的
Sweetie,
孩子
not everyone is meant to be an artist.
不是人人都是艺术家的
Making a career out of
你把自己的热爱
your passion
当成事业
is really not
这 这真的不是一件
a simple matter.
容易的事
You should ask your dad
不相信你问问你爸
about the struggles involved.
这中间的千辛万苦
At your age,
你这个年纪
you can't possibly understand.
是没法理解的
I'm aware it's not easy,
我就是知道不容易
which is why I need to
所以我现在
dedicate more time to painting now.
更应该抓紧时间画画
That's the only way I'll have the skills
这样我才有能力
to do what I'm passionate about,
才可以去做我热爱的
to pursue my dream!
我想做的事情
You're still young.
你还小
You don't have the capacity.
你没有能力
to finance your passions!
为你的热爱买单
Do you get it?
你知道吗
Mom, I...
妈 我不
Enough, no more talking.
好了 什么也别说了
You're staying home this weekend.
这个周末就在家
Just stay put,
好好地待着
and you're not allowed to go anywhere!
哪儿也不许去
No, I can't.
不行
I have a proficiency test tomorrow.
明天我有能力水平测试
I must attend.
我必须得去
What proficiency test?
什么能力测试
No, nothing is allowed!
不行 什么也不可以
Just stay home and reflect on yourself!
好好在家反省反省
I'm taking your phone!
手机没收
Darling...
老婆
What's wrong with you?
怎么回事你
Why did you get involved in this?
这种事情你也瞎掺合啊
You're ruining our daughter,
你 你害了孩子
don't you see?
你知道没有
Dad,
爸
you'll have my back, won't you?
你一定会帮我 对不对
Actually,
其实
your mom wasn't wrong.
你妈妈说得也没错
From our point of view,
站在我们的角度
we just want to
我们只是
make your future path
想让你未来的路
smoother.
平坦一些
Xiaohua,
小画呀
sometimes,
有的时候
a dream is just a dream.
梦想它只是一个虚词
When you grow up,
等你长大以后
you'll understand what we're trying to do.
就会明白我们的苦心了
What now?
这下怎么办啊
Xiaohua's been grounded by her mom
小画被她妈妈关在家里
and can't go to the exam.
不能去参加考试
Doesn't that mean she's quitting the exam?
不就等于放弃艺考了吗
Let's try to convince her mom.
那咱们去说服郭阿姨吧
That's not going to happen.
不可能
Her mom is very firm on this.
郭阿姨态度很坚定
Or maybe we can
或者我们把肖小画
sneak Xiao Xiaohua out
先给偷出来
and then distract her mom,
然后再把郭阿姨给引开
pull off a switcheroo,
来个偷梁换柱
a classic misdirection.
叫声东击西
It sounds workable,
听起来倒是挺可行的
but how exactly do we execute it?
但是具体怎么操作呢
Like in a spy thriller.
就像谍战大片那样
This is where our
这个时候就需要
top student needs to step up.
我们的三高出场了
But there's less than
可是现在离考试
three hours until the exam.
也就不到三个小时了
It's over.
完蛋
Don't worry.
没事
Our house often has
我们家线路
some electrical quirks.
经常有点问题
There is a way.
办法倒是有一个
What is it? How do we do it?
什么办法 怎么做
It'll all come down to our acting
那就要看我们的演技
and how well we work together.
还有默契了
Darling,
老婆
our daughter has been in her room
这女儿在房间里
for so long.
待那么长时间了
She must be hungry.
肯定饿了
I'll get something ready for her to eat.
我去准备点吃的给她
Hold it right there.
站住
Sit down.
坐下
Someone's at the door.
有人
Ah,
唉
I'll get it, I'll get it.
我去 我去
Who's there?
谁啊
How you doing, sir?
师傅 你好啊
Hiya!
你好 你好 你好
Here's the thing,
是这样子的
the folks upstairs mentioned
楼上的业主呢
their breaker tripped,
说他们的闸跳掉了
and they sent me down here to take a look.
然后让我来检查一下
What seems to be the issue at your place?
你们家是个什么情况啦
Oh, OK.
哦 好的好的好的
You're the electrician, aren't you?
电工是吧
It's me.
我 叔叔
Datou, who is it?
大图 谁啊
An electrician.
电工
He's here to inspect the wiring.
过来这个检修线路的
Our house always has issues
我们家不是一直
with the electrical circuit, right?
这个电路有问题嘛
Please check it out.
你赶紧看一看啊
What exactly is the problem?
什么情况
What could be causing it?
到底是什么原因
OK.
是的
This is your kitchen, isn't it?
这是你们家厨房 是吧
Yes.
厨房
I need to check the...
那这里要检查一下那个
OK, OK.
好的 好的 好的
Outlet over there.
那个插座嘞
Follow me, this way.
你跟我来 跟我来
I'll take a quick look at this outlet.
这个插座我看一眼哦
Hey,
叔叔
I've come to help Xiao Xiaohua.
我是来救肖小画的
I know.
我知道
Make sure to examine
你好好看一下
the wiring thoroughly.
这个线路啊
I'll test it with a voltage tester.
我拿电笔测一下了
OK, here...
这个东西
Where's Xiaohua at the moment?
小画现在在哪儿
She's been locked in
她现在被她妈妈
one of the rooms by her mother.
锁在里面的房间里
I'll lead you
等会儿我带你
to meet up with her inside shortly.
到里边跟她集合
Alright.
可以
Make sure to check thoroughly, OK?
好好看一下啊
What's the issue here?
怎么回事的啦
It's broken.
坏了呀这个
Broken? what do we do now?
坏了 怎么办
That's not good.
那不行的呀
I'll have to check
这个 你们家其他房间
the other rooms
是怎么回事
in your house.
我得看一眼
Got it, got it.
明白了 明白了
Where's your bathroom?
你们家洗手间呢
How about this.
要不这样啊
We'll start with
咱们哪
the room inside first, alright?
先到里屋看一下好吧
I need to take a look.
要看一眼
-Take a look. -Hold on!
要看一眼 站住
Is it really necessary to check
真的每间房子
every single room?
都要检查吗
Yes, ma'am,
是的嘞 这个
just in case.
以防万一
Right, just in case.
对对对 以防万一
The sooner we finish, the better, right?
早完早了嘛 对不对
Darling, just sit here.
老婆 你坐着
I've got this.
我来 我来 我来
Let me handle it.
我来就好了
Sit.
坐坐坐
Yeah, the keys.
对 钥匙
The sooner we finish, the better.
早完早了
You just sit here and rest.
坐坐坐 休息
I've got this.
我来 我来
This way.
师傅啊 这边啊
Over here!
这边啊 师傅
This way?
这边吗
Yes, this way.
这边
Let's start with the inside room.
里屋 先看里屋
The inside room.
先看里屋啊
Just a quick look, that's all.
看一眼得了 这个
Let's have a look, shall we?
看一下啊
Oh.
哎呦
What seems to be the issue?
哪里有问题啊
Where's the outlet
哦
in this room?
这个插座在哪里啊
It's over here, over here.
在这边 在这边 在这边
Over here?
在这边啊
I need to take a look.
要看一眼 要看一眼
Shh!
嘘
Lan Jinghui and the rest
兰靖灰他们
are already outside the building.
已经在楼下了
Pack your stuff.
你赶紧收拾好东西
Your dad will cover for us.
叔叔会帮我们
I'll get you out later.
到时候带你一起出去
Later,
等会儿
I'll try to distract your mom,
我想办法支开你妈妈
and then you need to make a move.
你们就赶紧
Is there an issue?
有问题吧
Why is this one also broken?
这边怎么也坏了呀
It's broken as well?
也坏了呀
What should we do?
那怎么办呢
Well,
这个
there's another scenario.
还有一种情况
It could be a leak from upstairs
就是可能是楼上漏水了
that reached the wiring,
接触到那个线路
you know?
你晓得吧
A leak?
漏水了
Right, it would cause a short circuit.
对 短路了就
We should check if there's a leak
那要看一下家里
anywhere in the house, right?
有没有哪里漏水 对吧
Yes, we should take a look.
对啊 要看一下了
Let's check it out.
看一下 看一下啊
Check it out.
看一下
Let's see where it's leaking from.
看一下哪里漏水了呢
Darling,
老婆 老婆 老婆
come on,
老婆 来来来
come here!
过来啊
Take a look.
看一下 看一下
Right here.
这里
When did it start leaking here?
这里什么时候漏水的
[It's leaking!]
漏水了 漏水了
[How did it start leaking there?]
怎么漏水了呀 那里
[Look, it's leaking.]
你看 漏水了
[Isn't that odd?]
奇不奇怪
Yeah.
真的呀
I've never seen
从来没见过
a leak here before.
这里有漏水嘛
How did it start leaking?
怎么漏水了
What's wrong with it?
怎么回事嘛这是
It's you, it's definitely you.
就是你 就是你
What's happening?
怎么回事啊
What, what's going on?
怎怎 怎么回事啊
Nothing.
没怎么回事
Nothing's happening, darling.
没怎么回事 老婆
Xiao Datu,
肖大图
step aside!
让开
Darling!
老婆
Xiaohua!
小画
They're here.
来了
They're here, they're here.
来了 来了 来了
Get in the car.
快上车
Let's go, hurry!
走 快快快
Driver, let's go!
师傅 开车
Xiaohua, Xiaohua, stop!
小画 小画别走
Xiaohua!
小画
Mom, don't chase after me!
妈 你别追了
If I don't go,
我不去
I'll regret it for my whole life.
我会后悔一辈子的
Xiaohua, stop!
小画 你别走
Xiaohua, Xiaohua!
小画 小画
Driver, stop the car!
师傅 停车
Xiaohua!
小画
Come back, Xiaohua!
别走 小画
Mom, are you alright?
妈 你没事吧
I just want to ask you one thing.
妈就想问你一句
If you're not allowed to paint,
如果不让你画画
will you regret it for your whole life?
你会后悔一辈子吗
If I'm not allowed to go,
如果不让我去的话
I'll surely regret it for my whole life.
我一定会后悔一辈子的
I will be responsible
我会为我的梦想
for my dream.
负责任的
Is this how you show
你这就是为你梦想
responsibility for your dream?
负责任的态度吗
You didn't even bring your ID card.
身份证都不带
How are you supposed to take the exam?
怎么参加考试啊
Thank you, mom.
谢谢妈妈
I'll do my best.
我一定会努力的
I definitely won't
我一定不会
disappoint you.
让你们失望的
Alright, alright.
好了 好了
Look,
你看
your friends are all waiting for you.
小伙伴都等着你呢
Go on.
快去吧
OK.
嗯
Go for it!
加油
Victory!
成功
[All the love in the world]
世间所有的爱
[is meant to bring us together.]
都是为了聚合
[If there's a kind of love]
如果有一种爱
[that's meant for separation,]
是为了分离
[then it might just be]
那恐怕就是
[the love of parents for their children.]
父母对孩子的爱
[Every parent hopes]
每个父母都希望
[their child learns to be independent]
自己的孩子学会独立
[and becomes strong.]
变得坚强
[But before that,]
但在这之前
[parents' love]
父母的爱
[is wings,]
是羽翼
[armor,]
是盔甲
[a fortress.]
是城堡
[It's all they can offer.]
是他们能做到的所有
[It's not brief enthusiasm,]
我不是心血来潮
[and it won't wear off.]
不是三分钟热度
[I've thought about it very carefully.]
我想得很清楚了
[I'm truly committed to it.]
我是认真的
[I'm aware it's not easy,]
我就是知道不容易
[which is why I need to]
所以我现在
[dedicate more time to painting now.]
更应该抓紧时间画画
[That's the only way I'll have the skills]
这样我才有能力
[to do what I'm passionate about,]
才可以去做我热爱的
[to pursue my dream!]
我想做的事情